[{'subject': 'Hannah chaplin', 'relation': 'gave', 'object': 'Birth', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'provided', 'object': 'Financial support', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Hannah chaplin', 'relation': 'developed', 'object': 'Psychosis', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Hannah chaplin', 'relation': 'entered', 'object': 'Period', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Hannah chaplin', 'relation': 'toured', 'object': 'English music halls', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'found', 'object': 'Work', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'joined', 'object': 'Fred karnos prestigious comedy company', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Teenager', 'relation': 'made', 'object': 'Impact', 'subj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Chaplins boss', 'relation': 'described', 'object': 'Process', 'subj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Caught', 'relation': 'was', 'object': '4 may', 'subj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'obj_type': 'DATE'}, {'subject': 'The essanay film manufacturing company', 'relation': 'sent', 'object': 'Offer', 'subj_type': 'ORG', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'The trampwas', 'relation': 'considered', 'object': 'Particular turning point', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Charile chaplin', 'relation': 'developed', 'object': 'Sad ending', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'High salary', 'relation': 'shocked', 'object': 'Public', 'subj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Mutual', 'relation': 'gave', 'object': 'Chaplin sr.', 'subj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'obj_type': 'PERSON'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'made', 'object': 'Films', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'demonstrated', 'object': 'Chaplin sr . increasing concern', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'produced', 'object': 'Short propaganda film', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'requested', 'object': 'Money', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'spent', 'object': 'Five months', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'DATE'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'wrote', 'object': 'Book', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Geoffrey macnab', 'relation': 'called', 'object': 'Geoffrey macnab', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'PERSON'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'arranged', 'object': 'Discreet marriage', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'begun', 'object': 'Work', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Hollywood', 'relation': 'witnessed', 'object': 'Introduction', 'subj_type': 'GPE', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Predecessor', 'relation': 'employed', 'object': 'Sound effects', 'subj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Chaplins performance', 'relation': 'give', 'object': 'Voice', 'subj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Great dictator', 'relation': 'spent', 'object': 'A year', 'subj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'obj_type': 'DATE'}, {'subject': 'Great dictator', 'relation': 'received', 'object': 'Academy award nominations', 'subj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'faced', 'object': '23 years', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'DATE'}, {'subject': 'Prosecuting lawyer', 'relation': 'declared to', 'object': 'Chaplin sr.', 'subj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'obj_type': 'PERSON'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'received', 'object': 'Subpoena', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Cast', 'relation': 'included', 'object': 'Members', 'subj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'boarded', 'object': 'Rms queen elizabeth', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Wife', 'relation': 'renounced', 'object': 'Wife', 'subj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Chaplins character', 'relation': 'cast', 'object': 'Accusations', 'subj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Ocean liner', 'relation': 'starred', 'object': 'Marlon brando', 'subj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'obj_type': 'PERSON'}, {'subject': 'Chaplins', 'relation': 'signed', 'object': 'Deal', 'subj_type': 'ORG', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Health', 'relation': 'prevented', 'object': 'Project', 'subj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'The academy of motion picture arts and sciences', 'relation': 'offered', 'object': 'Chaplin sr.', 'subj_type': 'ORG', 'obj_type': 'PERSON'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'revealed', 'object': 'Chaplin sr . unique working method', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'shot', 'object': '40,000 feet', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'QUANTITY'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'receive', 'object': 'Help', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'The film historian philip kemp', 'relation': 'considered', 'object': 'Chaplin sr . work', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Chaplins silent films', 'relation': 'follow', 'object': 'Tramps efforts', 'subj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Constance b. kuriyama', 'relation': 'identified', 'object': 'Underlying themes', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Pompous effects', 'relation': 'slow up', 'object': 'Action', 'subj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'took', 'object': 'Increasing interest', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Chaplins compositions', 'relation': 'produced', 'object': 'Popular songs', 'subj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'composed', 'object': 'Terrys theme', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'PERSON'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'received', 'object': 'Chaplin sr.', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'PERSON'}, {'subject': 'Limelight theme', 'relation': 'only competitive oscar for', 'object': 'An academy award for best original score', 'subj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'obj_type': 'WORK_OF_ART'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'influenced', 'object': 'Work', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Film historian mark cousins', 'relation': 'detected', 'object': 'Chaplins comedic style', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': '100 films', 'relation': 'included', 'object': 'Modern times', 'subj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'obj_type': 'ORG'}, {'subject': 'The british film institute', 'relation': 'established', 'object': 'The charles chaplin research foundation', 'subj_type': 'ORG', 'obj_type': 'ORG'}, {'subject': 'London', 'relation': 'includes', 'object': 'Road', 'subj_type': 'GPE', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'honoured by', 'object': 'Several summers', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'DATE'}, {'subject': 'Google', 'relation': 'marked with', 'object': 'Chaplins 100th', 'subj_type': 'ORG', 'obj_type': 'ORG'}, {'subject': 'Thomas meehan', 'relation': 'created', 'object': 'Musical', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'received', 'object': 'Awards', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'received', 'object': 'A special golden lion', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'LOC'}, {'subject': 'Chaplin sr.', 'relation': 'received', 'object': 'Academy awards', 'subj_type': 'PERSON', 'obj_type': 'NOUN_CHUNK'}]