[['Albert einstein', 'published', '300 scientific papers', 'ORG', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Loss', 'forced', 'Sale', 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['The twelve year old einstein', 'taught', 'Einstein algebra', 'PERSON', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Family tutor', 'devoted', 'Family tutor', 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'took', 'Entrance examinations', 'PERSON', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Alberts sister', 'married', 'Wintelers', 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'PERSON'], ['Wintelers', 'passed', 'Swiss matura', 'NORP', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Son', 'had', 'Breakdown', 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Son', 'spoke about', 'Love', 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'spent', 'Frustrating years', 'PERSON', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'acquired', 'Swiss citizenship', 'ORG', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Marcel grossmanns', 'secured', 'Job', 'PERSON', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'evaluated', 'Patent applications', 'ORG', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'completed', 'Einsteins paper', 'PERSON', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Membership', 'included', 'Paid salary', 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'influenced by', 'Romantic affair', 'PERSON', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'joined', 'Academy', 'ORG', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'received', 'The copley medal', 'ORG', 'WORK_OF_ART'], ['Albert einstein', 'expresses', 'Views', 'PERSON', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'visited', 'Palestine', 'PERSON', 'GPE'], ['Albert einstein', 'visited', 'America', 'PERSON', 'GPE'], ['Locker lampson', 'invited', 'Einstein', 'PERSON', 'PERSON'], ['Jewish invitees', 'totaled', '1,000 saved individuals', 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['The germans', 'was', 'The germans', 'NORP', 'NORP'], ['Albert einstein', 'expressed', 'Einstein appreciation', 'PERSON', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'submitted', 'Suggestions', 'ORG', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'developed', 'Appreciation', 'ORG', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'taught', 'Einstein', 'PERSON', 'PERSON'], ['Music', 'possessed', 'Unusual meaning', 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Music', 'took on', 'Pivotal permanent role', 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['The fbi', 'created', 'Secret dossier', 'ORG', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'experienced', 'Internal bleeding', 'ORG', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Nuclear physicist j. robert oppenheimer', 'summarized', 'Nuclear physicist j. robert oppenheimer impression', 'PERSON', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'published', 'Hundreds of books and articles', 'PERSON', 'CARDINAL'], ['Nuclear physicist j. robert oppenheimer', 'published', '300 scientific papers', 'PERSON', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'produced', 'E = mc2', 'PERSON', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'framed', 'Special relativity', 'ORG', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Hermann minkowski', 'reinterpreted', 'Special relativity', 'PERSON', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'adopted', 'Minkowskis formalism', 'PERSON', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'predicted', 'Phenomena', 'PERSON', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Researchers', 'confirmed on', 'Observation', 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'applied', 'Entwurf   theory', 'PERSON', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Equations', 'predicted', 'Static universe', 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Energy', 'make', 'Real tensor', 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Gravitational fields', 'play', 'Important role', 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Properties', 'led', 'Einstein', 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'PERSON'], ['Arnold sommerfeld', 'identified', 'Invariant', 'PERSON', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Und', 'die', 'Konstitution der strahlung', 'GPE', 'PERSON'], ['Idea', 'attracted', 'Attention', 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Earlier 1909 paper', 'inspire', 'Schrödingers work', 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Debates', 'influence', 'Later interpretations', 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'rejected', 'Second possibility', 'ORG', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'ignored', 'Mainstream developments', 'PERSON', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Mainstream physics', 'ignored', 'Einsteins approaches', 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'had', 'Shot collaborations', 'PERSON', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Co', 'invented', 'Einstein refrigerator', 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'permitted', 'Personal letters', 'ORG', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Albert einstein', 'expressed', 'Einstein interest', 'ORG', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Barbara wolff', 'told', 'The bbc', 'PERSON', 'ORG'], ['Corbis', 'licenses', 'Use', 'ORG', 'NOUN_CHUNK'], ['Decision', 'has', 'Legal impact', 'NOUN_CHUNK', 'NOUN_CHUNK']]